Friendship is thicker than honey
Maya the Bee Movie is a family, animation film directed by Alexs Stadermann.
A bubbly little bumblebee rebels against the rules of the hive to make all kinds of
friends—from violin-playing grasshoppers to a hornet named Sting.
Maya (voice), played by Coco Jack Gillies.
Miss Cassandra (voice), played by Justine Clarke.
Nurse / Thekla the Spider (voice), played by Heather Mitchell.
Buzzlina Von Beena (voice), played by Jackie Weaver.
Queen (voice), played by Miriam Margolyes.
Crawley (voice), played by Noah Taylor.
Maya the Bee (promoted theatrically as Maya the Bee Movie) is a 2014 animated adventure comedy film directed by Alexs Stadermann, loosely based on
the 1975 anime Maya the Bee as well as indirectly on the German children's book The Adventures of Maya the Bee by Waldemar Bonsels.
The first animated film in the Maya the Bee franchise, it was produced by Studio 100 Animation and Buzz
Studios, and distributed by StudioCanal in Australia and by Universum Film in Germany.
It features the voices of Coco Jack Gillies, Kodi Smit-McPhee, Noah Taylor, Richard Roxburgh,
Jacki Weaver, Justine Clarke, The Umbilical Brothers, and Miriam Margolyes.
Maya the Bee was released theatrically on 4 September 2014.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, but
grossed $29.6 million worldwide.
Two sequels to Maya the Bee were released: The Honey Games in 2018, The Golden Orb in
2021, and an upcoming spin-off titled Arnie & Barney scheduled for 2026.
The film explores themes of friendship,
anthropomorphism, european, 3d animation, cartoon bee.